Let me now talk to you about how Bootstrap and
现在 让我向你介绍一下应该如何同时使用 Bootstrap 和 jQuery
JQuery work together to support the Bootstrap's JavaScript competence.
来实现 Bootstrap 对 JavaScript 的一些支持功能
We saw that Bootstrap's JavaScript support is through the JS Plugins.
Bootstrap 对 JavaScript 的支持 是通过 JS 插件来实现的
These plugins are written in JQuery.
而这些插件使用 jQuery 写的
And we have already seen that the plugins can be individually included in our
我们已经学过如何单独地将某些插件 应用到我们的网页中
Web page, or collectively, the entire plugins can be included.
又或将整个插件组一起引用
We have also seen the relationship between JavaScript, JQuery and
我们也已经通过这张图学习了 JavaScript, jQuery 和 Bootstrap 中的 JS 组件
Bootstrap's JS components using this graphic earlier.
之间的关系
We have also seen that the Bootstrap's JS components can be used without
我们还学习了如何在 一行 JavaScript 代码也不写的情况下
writing a single line of JavaScript code by using the data attributes.
通过数据属性来使用 Bootstrap 的 JS 组件
But of course, if we need the full JavaScript API
但显而易见的是 如果我们需要使用 完整的 JavaScript 接口
to be used, then we can do that too by directly writing code.
我们就需要写一些代码了
Now in this section, we are gonna examine how we can write JQuery or
而这也就是我们在这一节需要做的事
JavaScript based code in order to control the Bootstrap components.
探索如何用 jQuery 或 JavaScript 代码 来控制 Bootstrap 组件
Let me give you a brief overview of JQuery.
让我先向你一个 jQuery 的概要吧
JQuery is a lightweight JavaScript library.
jQuery 是一个轻量级的 JavaScript 库
It is a feature-rich library and provides a lot of interesting
不过它的功能非常丰富 同时也提供了很多
methods that enable you to do HTML or DOM manipulation, so
操控 HTML 或 DOM 的方法
you can modify the HTML elements directly.
从而你可以用它来直接控制 HTML 元素
It allows you to add and remove CSS classes and do a lot of CSS manipulation.
它还允许你增加或移除 CSS 类或是操控 CSS
It allows you to respond to HTML events and
还允许你对 HTML 事件作出响应
upon occurrence of events, certain code can be executed.
并根据不同的的事件来执行特定的代码
It allows you to do effects and animations, and
它甚至允许你实现各种炫酷的效果和动画
also communicating with the server using AJAX.
同时还允许你通过 AJAX 去和后端服务器交互
Bootstrap's JavaScript components,
话说 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 组件
as we have already mentioned, is built upon JQuery.
就是用 jQuery 搭建的
Let's briefly understand the JQuery syntax so that it'll become more
现在让我们简单地学习一下 jQuery 的语法
easier to understand how we can control the Bootstrap's JavaScript components.
从而可以知晓如何通过它控制 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 组件
Now, the JQuery syntax starts with a dollar sign.
首先 我们通常会用 $ 作为 jQuery 语句的开头
The dollar sign is defining or access to JQuery.
因为 $ 会告诉电脑 我们接下来准备要用 jQuery 了
Following that, within parentheses, you will have a selector.
在 $ 之后我们会有一个括号 括号里面的东西叫选择器
The selector is what allows you to select a specific HTML element.
选择器代表的是一个特定的 HTML 元素
There are many different ways of specifying the selectors,
有许多方法可以用来指定选择器
as we will see in the next slide.
我们马上就会学到
After that, you will specify an action to be performed on the elements
在选择器后 我们将会指定一个作用在所选择的 HTML 元素上的动作
that match the selection criteria.
这个动作需要和所选择的元素相匹配
So, as example you see that I have specified within
如图所示便是一个栗子
the selector the value p there, and then the action as hide.
我选择了 p 这个 HTML 元素 并指定了 hide 这个动作
Meaning that when this code is executed,
这意味着当这段代码执行时
all the HTML elements of tag p will be hidden.
所有 p 打头的内容都会被隐藏
Similarly, the other example allows me to
类似的 我们还可以用 id 来选择元素
select the carousel with the ID mycarousel.
比如这里 我们就选择了 id 为 mycarousel 的轮播元素
And then make the carousel pause by specifying
然后我们指定了 carousel 'pause' 动作
the action as carousel with the parameter pause there.
意味着这将会使指定轮播的滚动停止
Let's take a look at Bootstrap's JQuery example here.
现在让我们来看一个完整的例子
Now, as you can see, the code is enclosed inside the script tags.
如图所示 这些代码被框进了 script 标签中
In this code, you can see that we have specified that for the document,
在这段代码中 我们可以看到我们指定了 document 元素和 ready 动作
when the document is ready, then the function will be executed.
意味着当整个 Bootstrap 文档准备好了后 ready 中的函数将会执行
The function itself is specified within the parentheses.
而函数是定义在括号里的
The function says that for those elements for
这个函数实现了如下功能
which the data-toggle attribute is set to tooltip,
让所有 data-toggle 属性为 tooltip 的元素
all those elements that match that criteria,
执行 tooltip 动作
then that tooltip action will be executed on those elements.
注意 中括号中的语句其实可以看做是筛选器
So, this is the way we saw that we can enable tooltips for
所以这就是如何让所有含有 tooltip 属性的元素
those elements in which we include the tooltip attributes.
都支持工具提示的方法
Briefly, talking about the JQuery selectors.
你是可以将
You can specify any HTML element as a selector.
任一个 HTML 元素指定为 jQuery 选择器的
So, any HTML tag, like p, button, etc., could be specified as a selector.
所以任一个 HTML 标签 比如 p 或 button 都可以指定为选择器
Which means that all the elements whose tags correspond to that
这意味着所有相应标签的 HTML 元素
will be selected by this selector.
都会被选为选择器
You can also uniquely identify
你也可以通过 HTML 元素的 id
a particular element by specifying the ID of that element.
来单独地指定一个元素
You can select a whole set of elements that bear
你也可以指定一系列拥有
a certain class or the CSS class associated with them.
一个特定类或 CSS 类的元素
So, you can specify all elements of the button class type or with button default.
所以你可以指定所有 btn 类元素或是 所有 btn-default 类元素
So, you can specify multiple classes and apply together for
你还可以同时指定多种类
an HTML element only those will be selected.
这样的话 就只有那些 同时拥有这些类的元素会被选择
You can also specify based on an attribute.
你也可以通过属性来指定
So, for example, you would say that an HTML element that contains
比如说 你可以只选择那些
the HREF attribute, only those elements will be selected.
属性里有 href 的元素
Or, we saw the use of the data-toggle attribute already for
又或像之前说过的那样
selecting those elements to which the tooltip has been applied.
只选择那些 data-toggle 属性 被设置为 tooltip 的元素
The current element can be specified as this, so
当前的元素可以用 this 来指定
which means that the current element will be selected by the selector.
使用 this 就意味着当前元素被选择器选择了
There are a lot more of these selector approaches.
还有其它很多选择器的相关方法 这里就不一一赘述了
Users' interactions with the Web page causes
很多情况下 用户与网页的交互
DOM events, to which JQuery provides methods to respond.
都会激发一个 DOM 事件 而 jQuery 提供了方法 去响应这些 DOM 事件
So, DOM events including mouse clicks, mouse in and
DOM 事件包括但不限于
out of a region, keyboard interactions,
鼠标单击 鼠标进入 鼠标移出和键盘交互
form-related interactions like clicking on the Submit button or
又或是和表格的提交
entering an information into a field,
以及往一个输入框输入信息
selecting and de-selecting a field.
选择中或取消选择一个输入框
Or even, the entire document window
或甚至 对整个 document 窗口的操作
getting loaded, resized, unloaded.
比如载入 重载大小或卸下窗口
All these would cause DOM events, to which JQuery provides methods for responding to.
所有的这些 DOM 事件都可以用 jQuery 方法 去响应
Let's take the example of the Bootstrap carousel to understand how they can
让我们用 Bootstrap 中的轮播作为例子 来更好地理解
use Bootstrap's JavaScript methods together with the jQuery methods.
如何运用 JavaScript 方法和 jQuery 方法
As we have already learned,
正如我们学过的
Bootstrap JavaScript components can be used purely by the data attributes.
Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 组件可以通过设置数据属性来使用
So for the carousel itself, there are four data attributes that can be used,
而对于轮播 如图所示
as shown in this slide here.
我们可以设置四种数据属性
For controlling a carousel using a JavaScript based control,
而若想用 JavaScript 来控制这轮播
we can specify, as you can see in the example here.
我们就可以这样指定
You can identify the carousel by specifying a selector as
选择器通过指定 carousel 类
the carousel class, and then use the carousel action on it.
来选出拥有 carousel 类的元素 然后对这些元素作出 carousel 动作
And as an example for the carousel action,
carousel 动作可以囊括之前用数据属性 设置的所有东西
you can specify setting the interval for
比如说设置间隔
slide transitions to be a specified value.
我们可以将轮播的滚动间隔调至一个特定的值
As in this example, the interval being set to 2,000 milliseconds or 2 seconds.
在这个例子里面 我们就将间隔设置为了 2000 毫秒 也就是 2 秒
The other JavaScript controls that carousel provides for
我们也可以设置其它属性
us is including carousel with the cycle parameter,
比如 cycle
which enables the cycling of the slides from left to right.
这是让你设定你的轮播是向左滚还是向右滚
You can use the pause, but I make sure to stop the carousel from sliding.
比如 pause 可以让你设定是否将滚动暂停
You can specify the number inside the parentheses as zero,
比如 number 可以让你设置滚动到哪一页
one or two, to specify that you want to go to that particular slide.
你可以设置为 0 或 1 或 2 来表示你要滚动到第 0 1 2 页
You can say prev and next to go to the previous and
你可以用 prev 或 next 来设置
the next slide from the current slide.
是否去往当前页面的前一页或后一页
Now, the carousel itself causes two events to be generated
需要注意的是 轮播本身在出现的时候
upon occurrence of certain events within the carousel.
会激发两个事件
One of them is the slid.bs.carousel event.
其一是 slide.bs.carousel 事件
This will be fired when the slide transition begins.
这会在滚动动画开始时被激发
The slid.bs.carousel event will be fired when the carousel has
而 slid.bs.carousel 事件则会在 轮播完成了向下一页面过渡的动画后
completed that transition to the next slide.
被激发
Now how do we make use of it within the jQuery methods?
那么我们该如何在 jQuery 方法中 利用这两个事件呢
As you see in this example, you can identify the carousel by its ID,
如图所示 你可以先用 id 来指定你的轮播
and then you can specify the on as the action.
然后你需要在之后指定一个 on 动作
And the on takes as the first parameter,
然后 on 动作接受的第一个参数需是 上述说的两个事件之一
the event to which this corresponding function responds.
就是你想要响应的那个事件
So in this case, we can say slid.bs.carousel and the function.
在这个例子里 我们想要响应 slide.bs.carousel
And inside the function,
于是在函数体内
you can specify what should be done when that event occurs.
我们就可以指定我们想要在事件被激发后 响应的代码了
In our next exercise, we are going to look at Bootstrap and JQuery working together
在我们下个练习中 我们将会看到 以上这些东西的具体实现
and we will see how we can add two buttons to the carousel that enable
我们还会在轮播中加入两个按钮
us to stop and resume the slide transitions.
这两个按钮允许我们暂停和继续轮播的滚动
And we'll see how we can activate those buttons from writing JavaScript code.
当然 我们将会学习如何用 JavaScript 代码去实现 【翻译 - Carefree0910】